Well, good day pilgrims and welcome to
another monk production and welcome to
this a review of the Sam ebike XD26,
a lightweight ebike perfect for
commuting, for recreation or for
fitness. the team out at uh Sam eBike
knew that I was in the market for an
ebike and they said here Steve take this
and see what you think. Grab your gear.
Let's go.
Well, this is how the bike was
delivered. It uh the bike weighs about
25 kilos I guess including the battery
which is pretty standard for most
ebikes. There are instructions inside on
how to assemble the bike along with all
the tools that you'll need for the
assembly. And there is an online
tutorial if you think you need more
assistance with the assembly of the
bike. I'll post the link for that video
in the description below. Let's go ahead
and open up this bad boy.
Heat. Heat.
How are you?
Heat.
It's
home.
Drifting.
Too late to catch the moon.
Baby,
we're drifting.
Too late to catch the
Baby,
we're drifting down.
>> Well, I've only been on the bike for a
few minutes, but already my initial
impressions are all positive. I've been
cycling recreationally for about 40
years. I'm getting older. the hills seem
to be getting steeper and I start to
tire a bit easier now than what I used
to. And so for that reason, I thought,
yeah, perhaps an ebike is an option. The
beauty about an ebike, certainly a pedal
assist bike like this, is that you can
have some assistance or you can have no
assistance. So, you know, if you feel
like working a bit harder, then just
turn the power settings off. Uh, and it
becomes all you. Speaking of power
settings, this has five of them. And as
I said, it's a pedal assist bike. If you
stop pedaling, you stop moving. And it's
got a sensor in it obviously that if it
feels like there's more pressure on the
pedals, then the motor starts doing more
work. So yeah, five power settings. It
will max out at 25 km an hour. That's an
Australian standard here. Uh other
countries may be different. And I
believe you can tweak it so that you can
get it to go up to 40 km an hour, which
is what about 25 mph, I guess. But I
won't bother doing that. I'll leave it
at 25 ks an hour. And in a lot of cases,
as I'm cycling, I sort of average around
about 22 to 24 km an hour. So, the motor
will be doing a little bit of work, not
much. And if I feel like making myself
work a bit harder, then I'll just
turn the power assist off. And of
course, that's going to prolong battery
life as well. Uh the way I ride on flat
level surfaces generally I'd expect
maybe 100ks out of a battery out of a
full charge but of course as soon as you
start using the pedal assist that's
going to change and of course the
terrain and whether you're riding into a
headwind or not but in the main I I
would expect yeah about 100 km out of a
full charge. Talking about pedal assist
and no pedal no assist it does have a
effectively a throttle on it as well. So
if you get completely knackered, you
could always use that and even without
pedaling, it'll get you to about I think
20 km an hour. So yeah, initial
impressions pretty good. Aluminium
frame, quality finish on the on the
frame. Sevenspeed Shimano gears. So
quality stuff there. Front and rear
shock absorbers to smooth out any bumps.
Upright riding position, which is good.
The electric motor in this case is in
the hub, the rear hub. 26-in spoked
wheels. As I said, it does have P five
different power settings, easily
adjusted on the instrument panel,
and it's got a uh a very easy to read
screen, which tells you how fast you're
going, which power setting you're in,
and some other information.
Baby,
you
Too late.
Too late to catch.
>> So, this is when an ebike comes into its
own. I'm going up a hill. Video footage
doesn't doesn't do the hill justice. the
slope, the degree of slope. I normally
struggle up this might be down to about
8 or 10 km an hour
and now I'm comfortably doing 20
with no sign of a sweat. So yeah, it's
times like this and going into a
headwind that I really appreciate the
benefits of an ebike
make cycling so much more pleasurable.
The beauty of this ride for me,
and I do it most days, it's about 20
kilometers
around Lake Junelup.
But the beauty is the wildlife, you
know. There's Mother and Joey.
Maybe a little bit hard to see. There we
go. It's all right, Skip. It's all
right.
Oopsie.
Yeah, they got no natural predators here
around the lake.
Maybe foxes which were introduced into
this country by the Brits
as a game animal for hunting.
But otherwise, yep, they lead a blessed
life. They skip.
This is another hill that I struggle
with and it's towards the end of my ride
most days. So yeah, I don't uh
I do not look forward to this part of
the journey, but in this case, it's uh
it's a walk in the park.
Well, I've had the bike for a little
while now. I've actually covered a
little over 60 kilometers over the last
few days. Uh Jackie, my wife, she took
it for a ride yesterday
and even without prompting,
she said uh that the seat is really
comfortable and that's got to that's got
to pay dividends. The other thing she
mentioned was the screen. It's a really
easy to read screen
even in full sun.
And the third thing she mentioned was
the ergonomic hand hand grips. These
actually provide support to the heel of
your of your hand, which obviously
reduces fatigue, which has got to be a
bonus when you're sitting in the upright
position. So, yeah, for for her to say
that, they clearly are standout features
of this bike.
Well, in summary, as I said a little
while ago, the more I ride this bike,
the more I enjoy riding it. And the
beauty is it's affordable. You don't
have to sell a kidney to be able to buy
one. But look, if you think this might
be the right bike for you or in fact one
of their other many bikes, be it
foldable or or or off-road,
go and have a look at their website.
I'll leave a link in the description
below for this particular bike, the
XT26,
but I'll also leave a link to their
website. And I'm pretty sure that
there'll probably be some discount for
YouTube viewers. So, yeah, have a look
at what they have to offer. Look.
Anyway, um this being the final
approach. You know what that means?
See you on the other side.
We're drifting.
Too late to catch the moonlight.
We're drifting
too late to catch